# **Preston C. Doris**

https://www.prestondoris.com ■ Phone: (925) 519-5071 ■ Email: preston@prestondoris.com

I'm an ambitious, personable, self-starting, optimistic, and self-taught Web Developer with two years experience independently building websites. I also bring several years of experience managing people and daily operations in a production setting on a professional scale. I have excellent math, critical thinking, and problem solving abilities, as well as a professional attitude. I have a passion and an insatiable desire to learn and grow which lead me to designing and developing my own Resume/CV website from the ground up and building a web based beer recipe builder to expand my professional skills.

## **Education**

## California Polytechnic State University San Luis Obispo

Bachelor of Science: Mathematics

Coursework: C Programming, Linear Algebra, Game Theory, Real Analysis, Differential Equations, Abstract Algebra, Combinatorics, Probability, Statistics, Classical Physics

## Udemy

Complete Web Developers Course 2.0: Certificate of Completion

Coursework: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Wordpress, PHP, MySQL, APIs

The Web Developer Bootcamp: Certificate of Completion

Coursework: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MongoDB, Express

Cambridge Certification Authority

Certificate: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP

CodeCademy

Certificate: Learn HTML, Learn CSS, Learn JavaScript, Make a Website

University of California Davis Extension

Master Brewers Program: IBD Diploma in Brewing; Professional Brewers Certificate

Coursework: Mashing Biochemistry, Packaging Engineering, Hop Chemistry and Analysis, Water Chemistry, Malt Biochemistry, Fluid Flow, Heat and Mass Transfer, Biochemistry of Yeast

# Experience

### Web Developer

Independent: 2015 to Present

Built a fully responsive personal Resume/CV website using HTML, CSS, CSS animations, JavaScript, PHP, and Responsive Web Design principles

Built a fully responsive Marketing App Landing page using Bootstrap as the framework for the responsive design Built a fully responsive simple Weather App leveraging an API integration through Open Weather Map to deliver the user current temperature, the highs and lows for the day, and the forecast for the day

Currently building a web-based beer recipe builder leveraging a unique algorithm I developed as a way to consistently create/adjust recipes

# 21<sup>st</sup> Amendment Brewery

**Production Manager:** 11/2016 to Present

Planned and forecasted production needs 2-3 months in advance leveraging an algorithm-based model I developed while actively adjusting current production schedules on the fly as needed to cover unforeseen spikes in sales

Coached and maintained collaborative relationships with each team members through thoughtful leadership and career developing mentorship

Managed a team of 10 people while managing and overseeing all beer production, packaging, and shipping from two production facilities on opposite sides of the country through 12% growth compared to an industry growth at 5%

Tracked and maintained daily, weekly, and monthly inventories for raw materials, packaging materials, and finished beer for two production facilities

Filed Federal Excise Taxes on shipped beer twice a month and a Brewers Report of Operations monthly from both production facilities for the Federal Government

Head Brewer: 12/2015 to 11/2016

Developed an algorithm to accurately calculate beer recipes in a production environment taking into account variations in raw materials that occurred from supplier to supplier

Worked with brewers to examine and test ways to improve efficiency and yield

#### Brewery Operations Supervisor: 1/2015 to 12/2015

Managed 100% of all production at our off site Partner Brewery through 30% growth while being responsible for all shipping logistics for the company

Tracked all beer production from start to finish to insure quality standards were met from our Partner Brewery

### **Brewery Production Assistant:** 4/2013 to 1/2015

Developed multiple excel algorithms to display specific trends in production and shipping, all of which are still in use today.

Managed all shipping logistics for the company while assisting the Production Manager with overseeing production from our Partner Brewery.

## Lagunitas Brewing Company

Brewer: 6/2012 to 4/2013

Operated a 200 barrel brewhouse with Siemens Brewing control system, varying size cylindro-conical fermenters, Allen Bradley control systems, Alpha Laval Centrifuge

Initiated and monitored an ongoing experiment to increase yeast harvest yields

Promoted after three months where I conducted filtration runs on an Alfa Laval centrifuge

Conducted yeast cell counts during yeast pitching and after first day of fermentation.

## **Drake's Brewing Company**

**Brewery Intern**: 3/2012

Assisted with all aspects of the brewing process from additions of raw materials for brewing to packaging finished beer

## Clovis Unified School District

#### Instructional Assistant II: 2/2011 to 12/2011

Assisted Special Education teachers through direct instruction of students, raising the student's scores by 25%

Assisted a Special Education Student in a one on one setting while seeing a 20% rise in their grade over the course of a semester

Assisted teachers with Special Education students in regular education classrooms

#### El Corral Bookstore

### Supervising Merchandising Associate: 9/2008 to 10/2010

Merchandising Associate: 1/2007 to 9/2008

Supervised ten student employees in the Student Supplies department for the #1 Student Store in the CSU system for sales per full time enrolled students

Followed and developed regimented training programs for the instruction of new and current employees

Developed team-oriented training programs to help assure product quality and timely inventory processes

Maintained communication with regular vendors for placing and receiving purchase orders plus troubleshooting issues that arose

Gained valuable leadership skills by creating and managing student work schedules, planning and leading staff meetings, and assisting in the hiring of new employees

## **Skills**

**Programming:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, PHP, MySQL; **Additional Special Skills:** Responsive Web Design, UX/UI Design, Wordpress, Wix, Word, Excel, and PowerPoint;